Command (Jet): Hunter, do you copy?
Hunter: I'm here, Command, prepping to land on the planet.
Command: Good. Remain on comms till you're needed.
Hunter: Okay. I'll be here. Landing now.
Mono: Hunter, where the fuck are we?
Hunter: Oooo. Language, Mono. We're somewhere out in Backspace.
Mono: What the fuck are we doing out in BackSpace?
Hunter: We're looking for a pod.
Hunter: Go scan for dangerous life forms.
Mono: Scanning
Mono: I really doubt there's anyone out here.
Mono: Still scanning.
Mono: Nothing detected.
Hunter: Hey, Command, I found the pod, but there's no sign of the crew.
Command: Alright. Stay put.
Command: Don't move.
Falcon 5: I see you, looking for the blackhole, are we?
Hunter: You want me to go look for them?
Command: Just. Please. For once. Do as you're told.
Mono: Scanning.
Mono: Still nothing detected.
Hunter: "Do as you're told..."
Command: We're still on comms.
Command: Everyone can hear you.
Hunter: Right. Listen, Jet, if this is about last night...
Command: Just. Please. We're sending another crew to your location now.
Mono: I've found another ship.
Mono: It appears to be a Falcon.
Hunter: Well, as long as its not a Falcon 5 we're good.
Mono: It's a Falcon 5. We're fucked.
Command: Glad to hear somebody is.
Hunter: Whoa... Wait... Wait... Wait... Wait...
[Gunshots]
Hunter: It's a Falcon 5! It's a Falcon 5!
Hunter: Shit!
Hunter: Shit! (Breathing heavily) I'm outta shape, I'm outta shape.
Let's stop for a second.
Mono: What do we do now?
Hunter: Definitely not staying put!
Let's go find that black hole.
Hunter: I think we found the first crew.
[Gunshot]
Mono: Hunter
Hunter: Stop shooting at me! [Gunshots]
Hunter: Wuhoo-oooo. Mono? You alright?
Hunter: Mono? You okay bud?
Mono: Hunter, where are you?
Hunter: You okay, buddy?
Mono: I can't feel my legs.
Mono: I really wanted to see the blackhole.
Hunter: Hey! You'll be fine.
We'll just reboot you and... -
Mono: Everything's going dark.
Hunter: Come on...
Hunter: I have eyes on the blackhole.
Command: Don't go in. Just stay put.
We'll send a team to check it out.
Hunter: You! You just want me to wait?
Come on!
Command: Do. As. You're. Told.
Stay put.
Hunter: (laughing to himself)
Hunter: No.
Command: What do you mean no?
Hunter: Adventure awaits.
- Mayday! Mayday!
This is Lieutenant Kaya Torres of the DSB Intrepid.
(inaudible panicked yelling)
Mayday. This is Kaya Torres.
I'm a sole survivor of the DSB Intrepid.
Everyone else has gone.
I don't know how I'm getting out of this one mama.
Mayday. Mayday. This is Kaya Torres.
Please respond.
Mayday. Mayday. This is Lieutenant Kaya Torres.
Cosmic beings, space pirates.
Come on, throw me a bone here.
This is Lieutenant Kaya Torres, please respond.
- [Voice On The Radio] Hello?
- Yes.
- Hello? - Yes,
- Can you hear?
- Yes! Yes!
Why's the fucking signal so-fucking gravity.
Survey says,
3543% increase.
Yeah. That should work.
Hello stranger.
My name is Kaya Torres.
I'm marooned on my life pod.
I have a busted ship
and I am circling a black hole against my will.
Please send help.
- Kaya Torres
Oh, a real actual person
wish I could say I'm sending a rescue crew but...
I'm in the same situation you are,
not circling black hole though.
Did you take a wrong turn?
Navigation didn't have the latest,
here's a black hole you shouldn't fly here update?
- Funny.
- Honestly I'm surprised you reached me at all,
the atmosphere here.
Oh, did I mention I'm on a planet?
I'm a cartographer.
I make maps for a living I did until I crashed on a rock
so massive it wouldn't let me back out.
Gravity,
always fun.
I've been trying to initiate a proper call link
between your gravity problems and mine
we have a serious time displacement going on,
Kaya Torres from the doomed Intrepid
If you want an interstellar pen pal,
feel free to drop me a line.
No one should be alone out there.
- So what do I call you?
Map boy?
I've been busy fighting physics.
This pod has just enough juice to keep me from,
getting swallowed up.
But if I modify the power flow
I think I can punch my way out of the well,
that's the idea anyway.
You don't realize how quiet space can be
until you're drifting in it.
I thought I'd be okay but fuck
I could really use a pen pal right now.
- You're still there.
I wasn't expecting to hear from you again.
Hammer. My name is Hammer
- Hammer?
- Yes. That's my real actual name.
I think my father wanted me to be a blacksmith or a lawman.
Definitely not a cartographer.
You hear that?
It's a massive sand storm going on outside my cave
planet has them constantly.
You'd die if you stood in the middle of one,
they scare me. Every time.
is fuck a curse word?
Fuck.
A little click at end.
Lovely.
- How have you never heard the glory which is the F word?
It's fucking timeless.
Also why cartography?
Was it to get back to your parents for naming you Hammer?
- I wanted to explore.
find places no one had ever seen be remembered
for something when I'm gone.
Wow. That sounds really egotistical
when you say it out loud, doesn't it?
What do you do Kaya?
What's your passion?
I'm an engineer.
I tinker. I,
fix things.
When you're a mechanic,
you're constantly solving puzzles.
Space has the best puzzles.
- I've cooked this local abomination
of a vegetable 46 different ways.
Crispy, steamed,
fried, it doesn't matter. It's always disgusting.
At least you don't have to suffer through
pre-process rations and nutritional pills every day.
I'm eating a fucking mystery meat.
God, I miss meat.
Here's a list of foods I wish I was eating,
a block of cheddar cheese,
and avocado,
actually just an avocado.
- Nah they're long gone.
Yours?
- Used to be me and my mom.
She was a master mechanic,
lover of puzzles,
all around firecracker.
Taught me everything I know.
a few years ago she got methyl rash.
You're prone to it when you work in
the belly of a ship long enough.
Then the lining in your lungs breaks down and,
it's shitty how frail we are.
What's your biggest fear Hammer?
you can trust me I won't tell.
- To be forgotten.
What's yours?
- To die alone.
No!
No no no no no no.
Ahh!
It put me even closer than before.
Trying to conserve resources as much as I can.
I'm losing ground.
Bit by bit.
Maybe I should stop trying.
One final adventure.
There are worse ways to go right?
I'm so scared Hammer.
- Hey,
don't give up.
I'm not going anywhere.
I'll keep my line open okay?
One of us needs to escape.
- Hey,
can I get a picture of you?
I want to put a face to this voice.
- Words don't do you justice Kaya.
- Guess what I'm drinking?
Vodka.
It's supposed to be for cleaning.
I have a confession.
I have been thinking about you.
And I kind of wish
I was on that planet right now.
I don't know what vodka is, but I like the mood
it's putting you in.
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, hold on. Wait.
You don't know what vodka is?
How?
I'm beginning to wonder if you're real at all.
Explain sir,
- is my sheltered upbringing showing? Figures.
This is what I get for being raised on Tremamine.
- Tremamine
- I suppose you're going to tell me I wouldn't be fit for,
- coupling either?
Let it be known, I am fully knowledgeable in,
such things,
if you were here.
- Timeout, I've never heard of Tremamine,
is it near Titan?
Jupiter?
Is it one of those weird Jupiter moons?
No one talks about?
- Jupiter?
Titan?
Kaya, I've memorized every colonized system.
I've never heard of those planets.
How is that possible?
- No fucking way.
- Hammer I'm sending you an energy signature.
Do a scan on your end tell me what you find.
- Fuck. I found it,
but the signal's reversed.
What does that mean?
- It's the little stuff.
It's the different curse words.
It's the different planets.
The alcohol,
your messages come in at the same delay every time.
What if you heard my broadcast
because it's not a black hole at all?
I mean shit What if it-
What if it's a wormhole?
But not to another spot in the galaxy, it's um,
to another universe, Hammer.
You're in an alternate universe.
And I think I can get to you.
Slow down, remember gravity.
Even if what you're orbiting isn't a black hole,
you can be crushed just by crossing over.
I can't fix my bucket of a ship without your help Kaya.
Don't plow into the unknown on a hunch.
Don't leave me.
- There's nothing left the other way.
Not anymore.
If I burn full throttle, I can make it to your planet.
Someone's got to save your sorry ass.
We're going to escape together.
That's how we solve this puzzle.
Hang on hammer. I'll see you soon.
(multiple voices screaming)
- No one should be alone out there.
Hello Kaya.
If you're watching this,
it means you finally made it.
I'm glad you did.
You're probably confused right now.
If you want to know the answer,
its gravity.
Your favorite subject.
You traveled through the wormhole,
time on your end has slowed down,
what you experienced in days.
In the meantime, I tried my best.
I did.
There's a storm coming in and,
I think I wanna go for a walk.
There's worse ways to go huh?
I waited as long as I could Kaya.
I'm so tired.
I left some recordings for you on this terminal.
At least one a day. Every day.
And hopefully it'll keep you from being so lonely.
If you fix my ship,
and you get off this rock,
don't forget about me.
I never forgot about you.
- Hello, new universe.
My name is Kaya Torres.
I'm trapped on a planet in the middle of fucking nowhere.
I have two busted ships,
and my odds of escaping are terrible.
But I'm alive.
So if you need someone to talk to drop me a line.
No one should be alone out there.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Mavis?
Hello, Kainoa.
I'm not getting a reading from your transport.
No shit.
It's totaled.
That's strange.
We just did maintenance on it.
I'll run diagnostics.
How's comms really doing?
Still down.
I'm afraid we're on our own.
Give me my distance from home.
Base 5 is 9.76 kilometers southwest
of your current position.
OK, plot a route for me.
Gravitational waves are currently in sector 10
and moving northwest at three kilometers per hour.
You should be in the clear.
Good.
Keep me updated.
And Mavis, prepare a fresh O2 canister for me, yeah?
Copy that.
You need to move now.
You have just enough to get back to base.
Tonight is the night.
Uncle, what are you doing?
What are you doing?
Mom told me to find you.
Is that where you're going?
You see those two stars right there?
Those two?
Yeah.
But take your thumb like that, and line it up with the stars.
And that spot right above your hand--
that's where Uncle's going.
I don't see anything.
What's that star?
Oh, that one?
Maybe you'll go there someday.
Come on.
How's [INAUDIBLE] tonight?
The same.
He's a bit happier since Dad showed up.
Of course, he is.
[CHATTER AND LAUGHING]
Keala.
Yes.
Do we have beer?
Yeah, I know.
Oh, hi.
Good luck out there, OK?
We're really going to miss you.
Thanks.
Take care of yourself, OK?
OK.
We're really going to miss you.
Sure.
She hasn't let up since grade school.
Yeah, there's nothing she wants to be under that rainbow.
He hasn't been the same since Mom passed.
He needed you here.
We've been over this.
It wasn't possible.
Honestly, it wasn't my decision to make.
Hey, enough excuses.
Fix it.
Just a reminder-- the last downed peg is near the base.
Atlas Major sets in less than six hours.
We need the system up before then.
I know.
Or we miss our window.
Oh, that's right.
I forgot.
You know everything.
Not liking that tone.
Your internal settings need to be turned down.
Hm, sounds like a personal issue.
[SNICKERS]
By the way, I tried to review the transport maintenance logs,
but I'm blocked out.
It's scrambled.
That doesn't make any sense.
First the pegs.
Now this?
Something's not adding up.
I'll keep trying.
Look, let's just get through tonight.
How much further?
You're close.
You'll have a visual of home base
and the pit just over this hill.
That's what we're calling it?
[CHATTER]
Excuse me, everybody.
Can we gather around really quick?
Um, we're just going to-- no, no, no, no.
Where do you think you're going?
We're going to toast Kainoa before he leaves this.
Kainoa, ever since we were kids, I always
knew you were destined to do great things.
And we are incredibly proud to be proud of you.
Mom would be proud, and I'm trying not to think
of this as a going away party.
15 years is a long time for someone to be gone,
but you've worked so hard.
To your journey out there and your safe return home.
I love you, baby brother.
I love you.
To Kainoa.
(ALL) To Kainoa.
Dad?
Maybe you want to say a few words.
Warning-- rogue gravitational wave detected.
Brace yourself.
[THUMPING]
I would like to say a few words.
Hey.
When I became a member of this family,
I'd been so stoked to say that my brother is an astronaut.
And [INAUDIBLE].
[GRUNTS AND ROCKS CRUMBLING]
[MUFFLED VOICE]
[BEEPING]
Was that OK?
[INAUDIBLE]
I didn't know what else to say.
No, that was good.
Thank you so much.
Can you go check on Dad?
I'll check on Kainoa.
[BEEPING]
Your O2 levels are dropping fast.
There's a leak in your intake hose.
You need to patch it immediately.
You know where the emergency sealant is.
Hello?
Come in.
Copy.
I'm here.
Do I have enough to make it back?
Your CO2 levels are critical.
But I can still make it back.
There's enough time.
There has to be something I can do.
I'm so sorry, Kainoa.
[SCREAMS]
Kainoa, he's not entirely wrong, you know.
What if something happens while you're out there?
What if he's gone before you come back?
Why would he care?
Huh?
Why?
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
It's stupid.
You weren't here.
I was.
While you were at training, I watched cancer take Mom.
And when Dad fell apart, everything [INAUDIBLE] me.
You need to make this right.
Tonight is your last chance.
And you are going to regret this if you don't.
Kainoa.
Kainoa, you're too far out.
OK.
I'm going to finish this.
What did Grandma do?
She was a geologist.
Isn't that what Uncle Kainoa does?
Yes.
Geologists help us to learn more about the Earth--
what it's made of, how it's formed.
He wanted to be one, just like your grandmother.
Is that why he's flying up there?
Why are you so mad at him?
Didn't Grandma want him to go?
Jada?
Hey, Mom wants you.
I'm not trying to abandon the family.
There's nothing that's going to keep me from going, Dad.
But no matter what, I'm still your son.
I'm sorry that I wasn't here when Mom died.
I wasn't here to say goodbye.
I just wanted you to know that before I leave.
Kainoa.
I never wanted you to be anyone but yourself.
I just lost your mother.
I'm not ready to lose my son, too.
Dad?
We have a successful chain reaction
within the peg matrix and topographical and subterranean
data coming in clear.
Connection with Atlas Major established.
You did it.
Initiate corporate correspondence transmission.
Kainoa Kalewa, chief geoengineer of base 5.
I'm stranded near Sector 1 with a depleted oxygen canister
and suit breach.
I am unable to make it back to base 5
after transport malfunction.
Unable to determine cause due to data corruption.
Requesting internal review.
Over.
I still don't know what caused the energy pack to blow.
Everything in the data logs is blocking me out.
Shall I keep trying?
No, Mavis.
Just file it with corporate.
You know, if I had a physical body,
I'd come out there and carry you back to base myself.
Thanks, Mavis.
I appreciate that.
Mavis?
Hm?
Could you record one last transmission for me?
Personal.
It would be an honor.
Initiating correspondence.
I am Kainoa Kalewa.
My sister is Keala Morris.
Her husband, my brother-in-law, is Jacob Morris.
My niece is Jada Morris.
My mother is Jada Kalewa.
And my dad is David Kalewa.
Tell them I said I love them.
Tell them I said goodbye.
We did it, Dad.
Over.
MAVIS: Relaying transmission now.
Transmission received.
♪
[MUSIC SWELLS]
[ALARM]
[ENGINE STARTS UP]
[THUNDER]
[ALARM]
♪
[EYES TURN ON]
THIS PLACE IS MINE.
WELCOME TO EDEN.
[FOOT STEPS. GEAR STOLEN]
[GATE RATTLES]
♪
YOUR JOURNEY TO THE CREATOR BEGINS HERE...
I WILL GUIDE YOU TO THE NEXT LEVEL, BEYOND HUMAN.
ONLY I CAN HELP YOU RID YOURSELVES OF YOUR PRIMITIVE BODIES...
AND LET YOU TRANSCEND TO YOUR CHOSEN STATE... [SCAVENGER] HEY!
WHERE'S MY SHIT?! [MAN ON MONITOR] BESIDE YOUR CREATOR...
ALL OF YOU WHO ARE CHOSEN...
HAVE BEEN SPECIALLY PICKED BY THE CREATOR.
HERE AT EDEN...
WE TAKE THE ENERGY YOU HAVE HERE,
WE CHANNEL IT, AND WE TRANSCEND...
TO THE OTHER EDEN. [GLITCH] TO THE OTHER EDEN.
AND THIS EDEN...
IS YOUR JOURNEY FORWARD.
[SLOW CLAPPING]
[SLOW CLAPPING CONTINUES]
[WEAPON CHARGE]
SO GOOD OF YOU TO JOIN US.
WHO ARE YOU?
I AM THE GATEKEEPER OF THE CREATOR.
AND YOU?
IT DOESN'T MATTER.
HMM.
HOW DISAPPOINTING.
JUST GIVE ME MY GEAR, AND I'LL GET OUTTA HERE.
YOUR PATH LED YOU TO ME. I AM THE ONLY ONE WHO CAN SHOW YOU TO YOUR PLACE...
AS THE CHOSEN ONE.
TO ASCEND TO A HIGHER LEVEL, BEYOND HUMAN.
NOW...
AS IT WAS WITH ALL THE OTHER CHOSEN ONES...
I WILL NEED YOUR MORTAL SOUL.
YOU'RE INSANE.
YOU...
DESPICABLE...
PRIMITIVE...
DEGENERATE!
AND WHO ARE YOU?
A THIEF?
A SCAVENGER?
A RAT WHO EATS HIS OWN FECES?
YOU ARE A HUMAN FAILURE...
AND THE CREATOR, IS DISGUSTED WITH YOU.
YOU'RE OUT OF YOUR MIND...
YOUR CREATOR DOESN'T EXIST.
[CHUCKLES]
WE'LL SEE.
[GUNSHOT]
[ELECTRIC CHARGE]
♪
[MUSIC SWELLS]
IT'S YOURS NOW.
DESPICABLE...
PRIMITIVE...
DEGENERATE!
YOUR JOURNEY TO THE CREATOR...
BEGINS HERE.